[
 {
   "question": "What is a node?",
   "answer": "Any device on the network that actively transmits and receives information.",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a host?",
   "answer": "A node that serves as a beginning or endpoint of communication.",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is media?",
   "answer": "Physical path connecting nodes.",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is data?",
   "answer": "Information carried by the media.",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the smallest unit of data?",
   "answer": "Bit.",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a networking device?",
   "answer": "Node that functions as part of the network structure.",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What device separates collision domains?",
   "answer": "Switch",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What device separates broadcast domains?",
   "answer": "Router",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the first octet decimal range of a class A subnet?",
   "answer": "1-126",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the first octet decimal range of a class B subnet?",
   "answer": "128-191",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the first octet decimal range of a class C subnet?",
   "answer": "182-223",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the first octet decimal range of a class D subnet?",
   "answer": "224-239",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the first octet decimal range of a class E subnet?",
   "answer": "240-254",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the default subnet mask of a class A subnet?",
   "answer": "255.0.0.0",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the default subnet mask of a class B subnet?",
   "answer": "255.255.0.0",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the default subnet mask of a class C subnet?",
   "answer": "255.255.255.0",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the first octet high order bits of a class A subnet?",
   "answer": "0",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the first octet high order bits of a class B subnet?",
   "answer": "10",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the first octet high order bits of a class C subnet?",
   "answer": "110",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the first octet high order bits of a class D subnet?",
   "answer": "1110",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the first octet high order bits of a class E subnet?",
   "answer": "1111",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the address range of a class A network?",
   "answer": "10.0.0.0-10.255.255.255",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the address range of a class B network?",
   "answer": "172.16.0.0 - 172.31.255.255",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the address range of a class C network?",
   "answer": "192.168.0.0 - 192.168.255.255",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the loopback address?",
   "answer": "127.0.0.0 (127.x.y.z)",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the address for APIPA?",
   "answer": "169.254.x.y",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How many networks are available on a subnet?",
   "answer": "2^x where x=number of 1s set",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How many hosts are available on a network?",
   "answer": "2^y where y=number of zeroes set",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the rules for writing an IPv6 address?",
   "answer": "1. You can group multiple sets of \"0000\" with \"::\" one time.  2. You can drop leading zeros. 3. you can replace \"0000\" with \"0\".",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is the subnet mask used?",
   "answer": "It is used by the local workstation to determine which subnet it's on.",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is CIDR notation for a network with the subnet mask of 255.255.255.0?",
   "answer": "slash 24",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How many bits is an IPv6 address?",
   "answer": "128 bits",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the top level domain?",
   "answer": ".com, .net etc",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service translates a url to an ip address?",
   "answer": "DNS",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of DNS record translates url to ipv4 address?",
   "answer": "a record",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of DNS record translates url to ipv6 address?",
   "answer": "aaaaa record",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of DNS record translates a domain to a mailserver?",
   "answer": "mx record",
   "topic": "networking basics",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SSH?",
   "answer": "22/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is DNS?",
   "answer": "53/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SMTP",
   "answer": "25/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SMTPS",
   "answer": "465/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SFTP",
   "answer": "22/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is FTP?",
   "answer": "20 (data), 21 (control)/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is FTPS?",
   "answer": "989 (data), 990 (control)/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is TFTP?",
   "answer": "69/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is Telnet?",
   "answer": "23/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is DHCP?",
   "answer": "67,68/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is HTTP?",
   "answer": "80/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is HTTPS?",
   "answer": "443/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SNMP?",
   "answer": "161/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is RDP?",
   "answer": "3389/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is NTP?",
   "answer": "123/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SIP?",
   "answer": "5060,5061/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SMB?",
   "answer": "445/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is POP3?",
   "answer": "110/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is POP3S?",
   "answer": "995/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is IMAP4?",
   "answer": "143/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is IMAPS?",
   "answer": "993/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is LDAP?",
   "answer": "389/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is LDAPS?",
   "answer": "636/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is H.323?",
   "answer": "1720/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port is IPSec?",
   "answer": "4500 (NAT traversal mode), 500 (IKE), 50 (ESP), 51 (AH)",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is NetBIOS?",
   "answer": "137-138/udp, 138-139/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is RTP?",
   "answer": "5004,5005/tcp and udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is VNC?",
   "answer": "5900 +n, where n=display number/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What ports range are System Ports?",
   "answer": "1-1023",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What ports range are User Ports?",
   "answer": "1024-49151",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How are User Ports generally used?",
   "answer": "Software developers use them for applications.",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What ports range are Private Ports?",
   "answer": "49152-65535",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is DHCP?",
   "answer": "67,68/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is SCP?",
   "answer": "22/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is RADIUS?",
   "answer": "1812/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is TACACS+?",
   "answer": "49/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is Kerberos?",
   "answer": "88/udp (tcp for large tickets)",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is Syslog?",
   "answer": "514/udp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is MSSQL?",
   "answer": "1433/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is LZTP?",
   "answer": "1701/ppp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is PPTP?",
   "answer": "1723/gre",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What port/protocol is Jet Direct?",
   "answer": "9100/tcp",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on ports 20 and 21?",
   "answer": "FTP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What services run on port 22?",
   "answer": "SSH, SCP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 23?",
   "answer": "Telnet",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 25?",
   "answer": "SMTP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 49?",
   "answer": "TACACS+",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 53?",
   "answer": "DNS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on ports 67 and 68?",
   "answer": "DHCP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 69?",
   "answer": "TFTP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 80?",
   "answer": "HTTP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 88?",
   "answer": "Kerberos",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 110?",
   "answer": "POP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 123?",
   "answer": "NTP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on ports 137-139?",
   "answer": "NetBIOS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 143?",
   "answer": "IMAP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 161?",
   "answer": "SNMP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 389?",
   "answer": "LDAP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 443?",
   "answer": "HTTPS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 445?",
   "answer": "SMB",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 465?",
   "answer": "SMTPS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 500?",
   "answer": "IPSEC",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 514?",
   "answer": "Syslog",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 636?",
   "answer": "LDAPS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on ports 989 and 990?",
   "answer": "FTPS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 993?",
   "answer": "IMAPS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 995?",
   "answer": "POP3S",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 1433?",
   "answer": "MSSQL",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 1701?",
   "answer": "L2TP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 1723?",
   "answer": "PPTP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 1812?",
   "answer": "RADIUS",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 3389?",
   "answer": "RDP",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What service runs on port 9100?",
   "answer": "Jet Direct",
   "topic": "standard ports",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the difference between the OSI model and the TCP/IP model?",
   "answer": "Open Systems Interconnect (OSI) is primarily an education tool while the TCP/IP model is developed by the DOD to solve networking problems, and is maintained by the IETF.",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What OSI layer is TCP?",
   "answer": "Transport Layer (4)",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What OSI layer is HTTP?",
   "answer": "Application Layer (7)",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What OSI layer is responsible for character encoding, data compression, and encryption/decryption?",
   "answer": "Presentation Layer (6)",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OSI Layer 1?",
   "answer": "Physical Layer",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OSI Layer 2?",
   "answer": "Data Link Layer",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OSI Layer 3?",
   "answer": "Network Layer",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OSI Layer 4?",
   "answer": "Transport Layer",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OSI Layer 5?",
   "answer": "Session Layer",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OSI Layer 6?",
   "answer": "Presentation Layer",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OSI Layer 7?",
   "answer": "Application Layer",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for OSI Layer 1?",
   "answer": "bits",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for the Physical Layer of the OSI model?",
   "answer": "bits",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for OSI Layer 2?",
   "answer": "frame",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for the Data Link Layer of the OSI model?",
   "answer": "frame",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for OSI Layer 3?",
   "answer": "packet",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for the Network Layer of the OSI model?",
   "answer": "packet",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for OSI Layer 4?",
   "answer": "segment",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the PDU for the Transport Layer of the OSI model?",
   "answer": "segment",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What happens at the Data Link Layer?",
   "answer": "Locical Link Control and Media Access Control",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How are source and destinations managed at the Data Link Layer?",
   "answer": "MAC addresses",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How are source and destinations managed at the Network Layer?",
   "answer": "IP addresses",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What protocol assigns MAC addresses?",
   "answer": "ARP",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is ARP?",
   "answer": "Address Resolution Protocol, maps IP addresses to MAC addresses",
   "topic": "osi model",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What does the command pathping do?",
   "answer": "Windows command like tracert which pings each router 100 times (default) to generate packet loss and latency information.",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Does traceroute work in Windows?",
   "answer": "No, the command is tracert in Windows.",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What command returns active tcp/ip connections?",
   "answer": "netstat",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What does the command ipconfig do?",
   "answer": "In Windows, it displays settings for installed network interfaces, IPv4 and IPv6 addresses, subnet mask, and default gateway.",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What does the command ifconfig do?",
   "answer": "In Linux, it displays settings for installed network interfaces, IPv4 and IPv6 addresses, subnet mask, and default gateway.",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How do you open command prompt as administrator?",
   "answer": "cmd ctrl shift enter",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How do you traceroute in Windows?",
   "answer": "tracert",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What command displays DNS information?",
   "answer": "ipconfig -displaydns",
   "topic": "network commands",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is LACP?",
   "answer": "Link Aggregation Control Protocol",
   "topic": "routing",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How manysubnets does the mask produce?",
   "answer": "2^x where x=the number of masked bits (ones)",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How many valid hosts per subnet are available?",
   "answer": "2^y-2 where y=the number of unmasked bits (zeros)",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the valid subnets?",
   "answer": "256-subnet mask=block size",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the broadcast of each subnet?",
   "answer": "Highest number below the next subnet (last is always 255)",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are valid hosts in each subnet?",
   "answer": "Numbers between subnet address and broadcast address of each subnet",
   "topic": "subnetting",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is CHAP?",
   "answer": "Challenge Handshake Authentication Protocol",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the most secure EAP?",
   "answer": "Protected EAP (PEAP)",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Which forms of EAP use x.509 certificates for authentication?",
   "answer": "EAP-TLS and EAP-TTLS",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Which form of EAP is used by Cisco hardware?",
   "answer": "Lightweight EAP (LEAP)",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Which form of EAP is used by GSM cellular networks?",
   "answer": "EAP-SIM",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What protocol does a RADIUS Server use?",
   "answer": "UDP",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What protocol does TACACS+ use?",
   "answer": "TCP",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What company makes TACACS+?",
   "answer": "Cisco",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What supports more non-IP protocols, RADIUS or TACACS?",
   "answer": "TACACS+",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is more resource intensive, RADIUS or TACACS?",
   "answer": "TACACS+",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What technologies are covered by 802.1x?",
   "answer": "WPA enterprize and WPA2 enterprize",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the innermost layer of the Defense in depth strategy?",
   "answer": "Data",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the 2nd innermost layer of the Defense in depth strategy?",
   "answer": "Application",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the 3rd innermost layer of the Defense in depth strategy?",
   "answer": "Host",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the central (4th) layer of the Defense in depth strategy?",
   "answer": "Internal network",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "what is the 5th (3rd from outside) layer of the Defense in depth strategy?",
   "answer": "Perimeter network",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "what is the 7th (2nd from outside) layer of the Defense in depth strategy?",
   "answer": "Physical facility",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the outermost layer of the Defense in depth strategy?",
   "answer": "Users and organization",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What device is used to scan for open ports?",
   "answer": "Port scanner",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How do you prevent SQL injection?",
   "answer": "input validation",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What device is often called a sniffer?",
   "answer": "protocol analyzer",
   "topic": "security",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What servise should receive the highest Quality of Service (Qos)?",
   "answer": "VOIP",
   "topic": "voice",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a PBX?",
   "answer": "Private branch exchange",
   "topic": "voice",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is h.323?",
   "answer": "Most mature phone",
   "topic": "voice",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are 2 benefits of SIP?",
   "answer": "Open and extensible",
   "topic": "voice",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is SCCP?",
   "answer": "Skinny Client Control Protocol, Cisco proprietary",
   "topic": "voice",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a SIP trunk do?",
   "answer": "Connects IP PBX to PSTN.",
   "topic": "voice",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the most common legacy ICS technologies?",
   "answer": "SCADA and DCS",
   "topic": "industrial systems",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is SCADA?",
   "answer": "Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition, developed for large scale distribution systems.",
   "topic": "industrial systems",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is DCS?",
   "answer": "Distributed Control System, designed to extend process control systems in refineries and industrial plants.",
   "topic": "industrial systems",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the advantages of DCS?",
   "answer": "Real time data",
   "topic": "industrial systems",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is DAS?",
   "answer": "Directly attached storage.",
   "topic": "storage",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is NAS?",
   "answer": "Network attached storage.",
   "topic": "storage",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of memory is used in storage?",
   "answer": "RAID",
   "topic": "storage",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a Storage Area Network do differently from a NAS?",
   "answer": "Allocates at block-level and protects from simultaneous access by multiple hosts.",
   "topic": "storage",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a SAN use to",
   "answer": "Host Based Adapter instead of NIC cards, Fiber Channel, Fiber Channel Protocol (FCP) link speeds up to 16Gbps, SCSI for high level operations.",
   "topic": "storage",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What method is typically used to improve Qos?",
   "answer": "Best Effort method",
   "topic": "storage",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What method of prioritization expedites video, voice, or data traffic?",
   "answer": "Latency based",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What method of prioritization expedites network traffic?",
   "answer": "Time based",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What QoS method is included in the frame header?",
   "answer": "802.1p",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What role does a hyvervisor serve?",
   "answer": "Abstraction layer between host operating system and VM operating systems.",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a type 1 hypervisor?",
   "answer": "bare metal",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "what is a type 2 hypervisor?",
   "answer": "host based",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a host in regard to virtualization?",
   "answer": "Physical hardware that ultimately hosts all virtual infrastructure.",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is container virtualization?",
   "answer": "Host uses one OS and splits filing systems into containers.",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does a VM access the network?",
   "answer": "Virtual NIC (VNIC), hypervisor performs NAT, or bridged adapter to external IP.",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the NIST standards for cloud service?",
   "answer": "On demand self-service, broad network access, resource pooling, rapid elasticity, measured service.",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the major cloud service models?",
   "answer": "Software as a service, Platform as a service, Infrastructure as a service",
   "topic": "virtualization",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the two planes of Software Defined Networking?",
   "answer": "Control plane and data plane.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the control plane of SDN?",
   "answer": "Makes decisions about traffic flow, routing protocols, switching protocols, QoS�",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the data plane of SDN?",
   "answer": "Moves frames and packets through network,routing packets, scheduling queues, reading routing tables and ARP values.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is an example of a common Network Analyzer?",
   "answer": "Wireshark",
   "topic": "tools",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is an example of a common SNMP management software?",
   "answer": "HP Openview",
   "topic": "tools",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is an example of a common SIEM management software?",
   "answer": "Splunk",
   "topic": "tools",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the most secure version of SNMP?",
   "answer": "SNMPv3",
   "topic": "tools",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the Syslog severity levels?",
   "answer": "0. Emergency 1. Alert 2. Critical 3. Error 4. Warning 5. Notice 6. Informational 7. Debug",
   "topic": "tools",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the benefits of SIEM software?",
   "answer": "Aggregation, Correlation, Alerts, Log Retention, Analysis tools",
   "topic": "tools",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the difference between a proxy server and a load balancer?",
   "answer": "Proxy server caches common queries and serves them when requested, while load balancer spreads the load among multiple servers.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "A high discard rate may be a symptom of what network problem?",
   "answer": "Congestion",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a fault tolerant system?",
   "answer": "System which can continue to operate in the event of a critical hardware or software failure.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a high availability system?",
   "answer": "System with 99.999% or greater uptime (5.26 minutes downtime per year).",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is MTTF?",
   "answer": "Mean time to failure: average time it takes for a newly installed device to fail.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is MTTR?",
   "answer": "Mean time to repair: the average time to repair a serviceable device.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is MTBF?",
   "answer": "Mean time between failures: averave uptime between failures on a serviceable device.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is MTBSI?",
   "answer": "Mean time between service incidents: average time between failures including repair time.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is AFR?",
   "answer": "Annualized failure rate: percentage of units expected to fail in one year.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is RTO?",
   "answer": "Recovery time objective: maximum expected downtime from disaster.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is RPO?",
   "answer": "Recovery point objective: maximum amount of data measured in time to be lost in a disaster.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is SLE?",
   "answer": "Single Loss Expectancy",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is ARO?",
   "answer": "Annual Rate of Occurrence",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is ALE?",
   "answer": "Annual Loss Expectancy (SLE * ARO)",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is a Quantitative Risk Assessment measured?",
   "answer": "Annual Loss Expectancy (SLE * ARO)",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What term describes a redundant part which can be replaced without interrupting service?",
   "answer": "Hot swappable",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is backup power used to increase redundancy?",
   "answer": "Uninterpretable power supply (UPS), redundant power supply, or backup generator provides redundancy during blackouts, brownouts, and sags.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is RAID used to increase network redundancy?",
   "answer": "Redundant array of independent disks: saves data to multiple hard drives at once.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How are network topologies used to increase network redundancy?",
   "answer": "Mesh topology, NIC teaming, and port aggregation create redundant paths.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is load balancing used to increase redundancy?",
   "answer": "Failure of one server reduces performance but does not interrupt service.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does clustering increase redundancy?",
   "answer": "Multiple servers in a cluster can dynamically reallocate duties after detecting the failure of one or more server.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is virtualization used to increase redundancy?",
   "answer": "Flexible on demand solutions can be stood up quickly and automatically.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a hot spare?",
   "answer": "Spare component that is connected, powered, and ready to automatically take over if the primary fails.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a cold spare",
   "answer": "Spare component kept in storage until needed.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a hot site",
   "answer": "Fully operational site which can be activated in hours or less depending on recovery plan.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a cold site",
   "answer": "Site space is set up in advance without hardware.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a warm site",
   "answer": "Site is partially set up with some hardware.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a full backup?",
   "answer": "Backs up all files regardless of archive bits, and clears all archive bits.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is an incremental backup?",
   "answer": "Backs up files with archive bit set, and clears bit.  Saves all changes since last full or incremental backup.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a differential backup?",
   "answer": "Backs up files with archive bit set, and does not clear bit.  Backs up changes made since last full backup.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a snapshot backup?",
   "answer": "Backup is performed from a virtual copy of running system.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": true,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are some considerations for backups?",
   "answer": "Keep clearly labeled, secure storage, encryption, store offsite, data destruction.",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a policy?",
   "answer": "Formal identification of problem and scope.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a standard?",
   "answer": "Mandatory action or rule to support policy.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a guideline?",
   "answer": "Recommendation to users when specific standards do not apply.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a procedure?",
   "answer": "Step by step instructions.",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What are 4 mobile device policies?",
   "answer": "COBO, BYOD, COPE, CYOD ",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is COBO?",
   "answer": "Corporate owned, business only",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is BYOD?",
   "answer": "Bring your own device",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is COPE?",
   "answer": "Corporate owned, personally enabled",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is CYOD?",
   "answer": "Choose your own device",
   "topic": "policy",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the differences between major and minor updates?",
   "answer": "",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the steps of the change management process?",
   "answer": "",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a Qualitative Risk Assessment?",
   "answer": "",
   "topic": "risk management",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What are some mitigation techniques?",
   "answer": "Technology controls, policies and procedures, routine audits, incident management, change management.",
   "topic": "risk management",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the Risk Management methods?",
   "answer": "Avoidance, transference, mitigation, deterrence, acceptance.",
   "topic": "risk management",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is winserver.exe?",
   "answer": "Remote Access Trojan",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a virus do?",
   "answer": "Attaches milicious code to another file.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a worm do?",
   "answer": "Replicates itself by exploiting system vulnerabilities.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a trojan do?",
   "answer": "Masquerades as a harmless or useful program.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a logic bomb do?",
   "answer": "Lies dormant until certain condition is met.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "How does a watering hole work?",
   "answer": "Infect site to attack site's users.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the XMAS atack?",
   "answer": "Network probe using TCP packet with all flags set.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is fuzzing",
   "answer": "Network probe using random or invalid data in header fields or data inputs.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What is banner grabbing?",
   "answer": "Network probe sending routine packet to service.",
   "topic": "malware vectors, attacks",
   "netplus": null,
   "secplus": null
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of encryption protects data in transit?",
   "answer": "Transport encryption",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of encryption protects data at rest?",
   "answer": "Storage encryption",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of encryption protects data in use?",
   "answer": "Memory encryption",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is code protected from reverse engineering?",
   "answer": "Cryptographic obfuscation",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the difference between confusion and diffusion?",
   "answer": "Confusion uses mathematical complexity while diffusion breaks up patterns in plaintext.  Both have the ability to change half the bits of cyphertext with the change of one bit of plaintext.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the act of sharing a key with a third party?",
   "answer": "Key Escrow",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the main benefits of a stream cipher?",
   "answer": "High performance and work well with data streams of arbitrary length.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "For what use are block ciphers best suited?",
   "answer": "Bulk storage",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a drawback of ECB?",
   "answer": "Cannot provide semantic security, less secure as the message becomes longer.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is XOR?",
   "answer": "Exclusive OR function, receives inputs based on binary values outputting single binary value.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does CBC work?",
   "answer": "Does XOR operation on each block of plaintext using the previouz block of ciphertext combined with an initialization vector.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does CFB work?",
   "answer": "Cipher FeedBack, like CBC but more like stream cipher, enables encryption of stream values without padding.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does OFB work?",
   "answer": "Output FeedBack, like CFB with error correction.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does CTR work?",
   "answer": "Counter, stream cipher where each block's encryption uses an incrementing counter.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does GCM work?",
   "answer": "Counter mode with hash based authentication code.",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Nuemonic for symmetric encryption?",
   "answer": "32BRAIDS",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 1 (3)",
   "answer": "3DES 112 bit key strength, 80 bit effective",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 2 (2)",
   "answer": "2 Fish 128, 192, 256 keys, 128 bit blocks",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 3 (B)",
   "answer": "Blowfish 448bit 64 bit block",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 4 R",
   "answer": "RC4 Ron's Cipher 1-4",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 5 A",
   "answer": "AES (Rijndael) 128, 192, 256 key strength, 128 bit blocks",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 6 I",
   "answer": "IDEA",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 7 D",
   "answer": "DES 56 bit key, 64 bit block",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Symmetric 8 S",
   "answer": "Serpent",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Nuemonic for asymmetric encryption?",
   "answer": "DEERQ",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Asymmetric 1 D",
   "answer": "Diffie Helman",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Asymmetric 2 E",
   "answer": "El Gamal",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Asymmetric 3 E",
   "answer": "Eliptical Curve Cryptography",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Asymmetric 4 R",
   "answer": "RSA",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Asymmetric 5 Q",
   "answer": "Quantum",
   "topic": "cryptography",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is Diffie Hellman generally used?",
   "answer": "Key exchange",
   "topic": "",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What entity signs and revokes certificates?",
   "answer": "Certificate Authority (CA)",
   "topic": "PKI",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is OCSP?",
   "answer": "Online Certificate Status Protocol, shows status of certificate, sends request to ca over HTTP",
   "topic": "PKI",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is CRL?",
   "answer": "Certificate Revocations List",
   "topic": "PKI",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is static pinning?",
   "answer": "Browser publisher pins keys of high traffic sites.",
   "topic": "PKI",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is dynamic pinning?",
   "answer": "Uses IETF standard HTTP Public Key Pinning (HPKP)",
   "topic": "PKI",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is an ACL?",
   "answer": "Access control list",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the difference between IDS and IPS?",
   "answer": "Intrusion Prevention System takes action to stop or block suspected attacks while Intrusion Detection System only monitors.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What solution must you use to ensure that no network attack can be launched from one network to another?",
   "answer": "Airgap, complete isolation with no connectivity to outside networks",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What solution allows information to be sent one way into a network?",
   "answer": "Unidirectional gateway, allows data one way without allowing information out.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Can an airgap protect against exfiltration or malware?",
   "answer": "No.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How do you protect a network from all possible attacks?",
   "answer": "You can't.  It is impossible to protect against ALL attacks.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are some switch security features?",
   "answer": "Port security, MAC filtering, loop protection, flood guard.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the difference between a stateless and stateful firewall?",
   "answer": "Stateful firewall monitors session activity while stateless simply examines each packet.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does an application layer firewall work?",
   "answer": "They use Deep Packet Inspection (DPI) to find irregularities that can be missed by SPI.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the most secure network configuration?",
   "answer": "Dual firewall, DMZ protected by firewall and another firewall for interior network.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does a three homed firewall configuration work?",
   "answer": "DMZ and interior network are each separately protected by a shared firewall.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a dual homed server configuration?",
   "answer": "Bastion hosts sit outside the firewall which protects the interior network.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are some methods of Network Access Control?",
   "answer": "Guest network, posture assessment, and agents.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does a guest network protect your network?",
   "answer": "Because guests are only provided internet access, they do not have access to your network.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a posture assessment?",
   "answer": "Client is placed on a quarantine network until they are verified to meet security rules.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How is a honeypot used?",
   "answer": "Allows admin to detract and monitor intruder behavior.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is a WAF?",
   "answer": "Web Application Firewall (WAF) sits between network and web server.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are some load balancing techniques?",
   "answer": "SSL acceleration, data compression, health checking, TCP offloading and buffering, priority queuing, content caching.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What direction is considered forward for a proxy?",
   "answer": "Facing outward from the network.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What does a reverse proxy do?",
   "answer": "Mediates communications between internet clients and LAN servers.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Is SSL open source?",
   "answer": "No, SSL was developed by Netscape.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Is TLS open source?",
   "answer": "Yes.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What type of cryptography do SSL and TLS use?",
   "answer": "Assymetric key exchange, symmetric bulk encryption.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What direction do SSL and TLS authenticate?",
   "answer": "Dual authentication and one way are possible, but HTTPS usually only authenticates the server.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What applications use SSL encryption?",
   "answer": "HTTPS, FTPS, SMTP, SNMPv3, EAP-TLS, SSL VPN",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "Which protocols are included in secure shell?",
   "answer": "SCP, rsync, SFTP",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does S/MIME encrypt and authenticate?",
   "answer": "x.509 certificates",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What layer 2 VPN solution offers native support by most operating systems?",
   "answer": "Layer 2 Tunneling Protocol/Ipsec",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does PPTP work?",
   "answer": "Point to Point Tunneling Protocol (PPTP) sends PPP packets over GRE.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is GRE?",
   "answer": "Generic Routing Encapsulation (GRE) encapsulates L# protocol in a point to point link.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What protocols make up IPsec?",
   "answer": "Internet Key Exchange (IKE), Authentication Header (AH), Encapsulation Security Payload (ESP).",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are the two modes of IPsec?",
   "answer": "Tunnel mode and transport mode.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does Ipsec operate in tunnel mode?",
   "answer": "Encapsulates IP packet with AH or ESP.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How does Ipsec operate in transport mode?",
   "answer": "Encrypts payload.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the difference between FTPS and SFTP?",
   "answer": "FTPS uses SSL while SFTP uses SSH2",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the smallest network segment?",
   "answer": "Collision domain.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the fundamental unit of segmentation on a modern switched Ethernet network?",
   "answer": "Broadcast domain.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is commonly the best L2 segmentation option?",
   "answer": "Use VLANs to logically separate traffic on a physically switched network.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "How should network zones with different security needs be separated?",
   "answer": "Chokepoints, no traffic should be allowed to bass between networks without evaluation by a secured chokepoint.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What are some considerations in placing a chokepoint?",
   "answer": "They are a good place for firewalls and IDS and IPS, but ensure the chokepoint can handle epected traffic.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 },
 {
   "question": "What is the primary device for separating broadcast domains?",
   "answer": "Router.",
   "topic": "network defense",
   "netplus": false,
   "secplus": true
 }
]